# Anurag Dhamala

Software Engineer

# CONTACT

- +9779840347464
- anuragdhamala8@gmail.co
- Pepsicola, Kathmandu
- https://github.com/anurag-dhamala
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/anurag-dhamala/

# **SKILLS**

- JavaScript(Node.js React.js Next.JS) - Expert
- MongoDB(Mongoose) / Node JS (Express Js) - Skillful
- TypeScript Experienced
- Linux / Git / Docker Experienced
- Redis Experienced
- Software Design and Architecture
  - Experienced
- Svelte.Js Experienced
- Tailwind CSS, Material UI, AntD -Expert
- REST, GRPC, GraphQL -Experienced

# **LANGUAGE**

Nepali - Expert

English - Experienced

# SUMMARY

A software engineer with 3 years of experience in the IT industry. With an experience of building products from scratch to finish in my day-to-day job, I also love to work on my side projects during my off-time. I love to communicate with other people from the same field and share my knowledge.

# **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelors in Information Technology**

Texas College of Management and IT / Kathmandu / August, 2018 - January, 2023

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Team Lead**

Hamro Patro Inc / Kathmandu / July, 2023 - Present

## **Software Engineer**

Hamro Patro Inc. / Kathmandu / July, 2022 - Present

#### **MERN Stack Trainer**

Deerwalk Training Center / Kathmandu / August, 2023 - Present

# **Associate Software Engineer**

Hamro Patro Inc / Kathmandu / March, 2021 - July, 2022

# IT Intern

Texas Imaginology / Kathmandu / October, 2019 - June, 2020

## **PROJECTS INVOLVED**

## Let's Read Asia

- Built the front-end side of this project using NextJS.
- Designed the UI portion provided in **Figma** by client.
- REST API integration.
- Implemented **redux toolkit**, react context and other useful react concepts for the first time in this project.
- Used GCP and app engine to deploy the projects
- Collaborated with designers across foreign countries and with clients from Asia Foundation to successfully fulfill the requirements.

https://letsreadasia.org

# **Hamro TeleHealth**

- Built the WebRTC client in TypeScript for ReactJS project and later on migrated it to LiveKit.
- Designed the UI by cooperating with other front-end team members.
- Created some REST APIs in Spring Boot, Java.
- Mentored new coming members on how the web-rtc flow works.

https://health.hamropatro.com

## **Hamro Gifts**

- Worked on the admin side of this project.
- Integrated GraphQL on the client side and Leaflet.js
- Led the team later on for a while to revamp the project.
- Worked on the reaction-commerce (now mailchimp) and implemented new GraphQL schemas and MongoDB schemas in the backend.
- Integrated Stripe 3DS on both client and server side (NodeJS).

https://gifts.hamropatro.com

## **Hamro Chat**

- Designed the chat system architecture.
- Designed GRPC protos and integrated the GRPC in SDK.
- Introudced Unary GRPC interceptor on the client side to the fellow engineers.
- Designed and created the SSE server using Redis Pub/Sub model for real time message flow in Node. Js from scratch.
- Built the SDK for the client side so that any system would be able to call the chat system APIs if necessary by installing the sdk in their projects.
- Create the chat front-end from scratch in SvelteJs and integrated my own SDK.
- Built the React SDK as a npm package so that any react project would be able to integrate chat.
- Created its desktop application using Tauri and Rust and data communication between Rust and Javascript.

(Project is not publicly announced yet)

# **Hamro Chautari**

- Chautari is a video call platform like Google Meet.
- Worked mostly on creating the video calling platform in ReactJs using Livekit sdk.
- Customized the livekit sdk to my own and re-created the whole livekit UI.
- Guided on livekit server sdk to team members.

https://chautari.hamropatro.com

# Other Involvements as a software engineer

- Created in-house npm packages for the company and fellow engineers.
- Built headless CMS with **Strapi** and **Postgres** for the overall Hamro Patro content management.
- **Dockerizing** projects.
- Built SDKs in Svelte for the company.
- Taking care of web view sdk within the Hamro Patro app.
- Containerizing both front and back end projects for deployment in Kubernetes.
- **Mentoring** the incoming intern batches.
- Open source contribution
- Writing articles on HashNode. You can find me on: https://anuragdhamala.hashnode.dev/